# **Ida Shalilian**

Houston, Texas | (281)-241-9374 | <u>ida.shalilian@gmail.com</u> GitHub: <u>github.com/corgimaman</u> | LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/ida-s-86b21b68</u>

#### **PROFILE**

Full stack web developer that is capable of adapting to any environment, working independently but also does well in groups and tends to take the leadership role if no one else is willing. Experienced in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Node, as well as life's adventures, yoga, and environmental science/geology.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Environmental Consultant, EOSolutions, Houston, Texas — 2018–Present

Air permitting and compliance for oil and gas, managing multiple sites and deadlines. Regular duties included record keeping, federal and state rule program implementation, compliance, and reporting. Contributed to quality assurance, testing, and design assistance to the website and database we provided for our client.

## Yoga Instructor, LA Fitness, Houston, Texas — 2018 - March 2020

Taught hour long yoga classes to regular and new students, aged from 15 to over 80. Provided feedback and guidance for students. Employment ended due to the pandemic.

# Self Employed, Houston, Texas -2017 - 2018

Cultivated a clientele working independently as a caretaker.

## Graduate Research Assistance, Mangilao, Guam -2015 - 2017

Performed field work, lab work, and research writing as a graduate student at the Water and Environmental Research Institute of the Western Pacific (WERI). Worked with other universities, United States Geological Survey (USGS), military departments, and the Guam Waterworks Association (GWA).

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Rice — Full Stack Web Development Certification, 2021

University of Guam — Master of Science, Environmental Science, January 2017

University of Houston — Bachelor of Science, Geology, December 2013

#### **SKILLS**

Front-end Development, Mobile First Web Design, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, REST APIs, JSON, Bootstrap, Media Queries, command line, Git, GitHub, Node, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, APIs, ArcGIS, Microsoft Office, Azure, Photoshop, Photography and Videography, Video Editing, Farsi, rudimentary American Sign Language, SCUBA certified, Yoga Teacher Training 200-hour certified, backpacker around the world.